hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and I talk about ways
for coaches mentors and trainers to
scale their businesses now listen if
you're anyone like me productivity and
getting more out of the time that you
have is something that you care about
and so what I want to talk about today
is just one of my number one strategies
for
creativity um I've studied for a long
time about what it takes to get into the
Flow State into the right mindset to be
able to be creative to come up with the
ideas that we have and in our businesses
when I'm creating sales copy when I'm
writing content when I'm coming up with
ideas in my business um sometimes we hit
a a block sometimes we hit writer block
sometimes we hit a place where we don't
come up with those ideas and so what I
have found is that one of the most
productive things to do is strategic
Detachment in the form of strategic
distraction now you got to be careful
with this because if we con constantly
distract ourselves out of doing things
we're not going to have enough time to
do any of them myself I have two
kids uh one's 2 years old the other one
is 3 months old and I find that if I
don't stay on track I don't get done
what I need to in my business uh however
before I had kids I used to have
unlimited amount of time for creativity
I don't have that anymore but that's
okay because what that's taught me is
how to tap into those centers of
creative ideas when I don't have the
kind of time that I used to to utilize
the time that I have currently right now
and so what I do is I come up with ways
to detach my mind from focusing so much
on things when you're trying to come up
with ideas in your
business um focus focus focus on that
idea often doesn't produce the
creativity that we want to to come up
with the creative genius that we need to
and so what actually works is detaching
yourself from the thing that you're
trying to create so let's say that
you're trying to come up with an idea
for a webinar or a training or a course
or some Creative Marketing hook or
something that you want to sell in your
business focusing all of your energy on
thinking about those things on trying to
come up with it in your brain often does
not produce the results that you want
instead when you step away from it you
do something else whether it be watching
TV whether it be now I wouldn't
recommend scrolling social media because
that's triggering different types of
these parts of the centers in your brain
but what it is is when you can get
focused on something that is not related
to something that you normally do in
your life it does two incredible things
I was listening to an amazing book by Dr
Jo Jo Des Spenzo where he was talking
about how when people are meditating
that this happens and I thought about
this this is exactly what we end up
doing we have familiar habits and
systems and ways that we operate in our
life I have the familiar that I do every
single day in my business
and in my family life and often times
The
Familiar is where we lack the creativity
where we're like okay I go I'm going
through the motions in this so what we
need to do is we need to find ways to do
something that is outside of The
Familiar of what we normally do and we
put our focus on that thing okay so
taking care of my family building um my
business our personal life all of that
my creativity often doesn't necessarily
flow from doing those things but it's
when I can detach from it and I do
something that's outside of the ordinary
that gets me into a focused state which
the way I like to do it sometimes I'll
either play video games or I will go for
a walk or even when we're working out in
the gym because we're focused on one
very specific task that's outside of the
ordinary Norm of what we're doing now we
can sometimes create a habit of these
things and then the creativity
disappears and so again like I always
find I was doing this all the time when
I needed creativity I play a video game
and then the creativity stopped coming
when I was doing that because it
actually became my familiar Norm it
actually became the thing that I'm
always doing so that's what I want you
to think about I want you to think about
something that you've not done for a
while that you enjoyed doing that takes
Focus to get your mind off of the stuff
stuff that you have to get done and
often times when we do this creativity
for the ideas for the things that we've
been stuck on comes in and and again
it's it's often not going to be
something that you have a habit of doing
most of the time because it detaches you
from it this is why going on a vacation
people often say gives them incredibly
creative ideas this is why when people
are on holiday they have incredibly
creative ideas because being on the
holiday triggers the same outside of the
familiar Norm of Life of what we're
normally doing it triggers that in us in
a positive way and so what I've done is
I've created I look in my life and I say
okay I want to do things that kind of
when I'm lacking creativity I want to
shake up my Norm my habits my routine
just a little bit try something
different taking a different action
putting into motion the ideas that I
have and when we do this it unlocks
incredible levels of creativity which
then lead to incredible levels of
productivity so when the creativity
comes with something that is powerful
and creative and maybe you've not done
it a whole lot all the time right now
you know for me sometimes it could be
reading books um but then that becomes
the familiar normal and then I got to
take a break off of doing those things
so whatever that thing is that you find
okay I'm doing this and I get creative
and then suddenly you're doing it so
much that you're not creative anymore it
means that we have to shift it again it
means that we have to shift into doing
stuff that's outside of our our familiar
Norm to shift us in
into creative thinking it triggers the
brain to fire
neurotransmitters in creative
ways that it normally wouldn't because
we're outside of our normal routine so
that's really what the key is on this is
I want you to look at it's not
necessarily the the that that for me
playing video games does this it's that
when I'm playing a video game it's
outside of the Realm of the familiar
Norm of what I'm doing every single day
normally that it gets me into a focused
state of playing this game or doing that
and often times I'll play a new game
that I've never played before I'll I'll
watch a new movie or a new TV show that
I've never watched before and and
there's so much different things like
this but it gets me out of that familiar
Norm of what I'm used to experiencing
all the time and the creativity starts
to come back try this out I want to
encourage you that if you've been
lacking creativity in your business if
you say I can't come up with ideas I
don't know what to do I I just I just
don't know what to you're struggling to
make decisions this is one of the key
places where this works is that if
you're struggling to make a decision you
need to tap into those creative when I
talk about creative it's about creating
so when we are making a decision we are
creating something from these creative
centers in our body and in our mind
mind okay and so we get out of the
familiar Norm of what our routine is by
doing something that does require Focus
that's outside of what we normally do
that's why like I said when I play a new
video game it does this for me because
it's like okay I am focused on something
different than I've not normally been
focused
on and then it becomes the familiar
normal and that's when I know okay time
to either stop playing games or do
something else focus on that for the
creativity now we you don't always need
to be in a creative state of mind all
the time but what this does is this is
going to create a habit for you now that
anytime that you're struggling to make a
decision you're struggling to know what
should I do next you can go into this
habit space where you say okay I'm going
to shift out of the familiar Norm I
don't need to go on a vacation I don't
need to make a massive investment to be
able to do this I can do something
different outside of what I normally am
familiar doing to tap me into those
creative places and when you do this
when you make a practice of this like I
have you will notice that you actually
have unlimited levels of creativity when
you know how to Spur Inspire and tap
into them on demand and so again this is
what I love helping my clients with in
my wealthy coach Academy program is
knowing how to make the best decisions
what decisions move the needle forward
for them in their business and what to
do to make the kind of income that they
want as well so I'd love to see see you
in there I'd love for you to jump in
with us check out some of the live
events that we have over at my website
in the description below this as well
talk soon everybody good
[Music]
[Applause]